# John Somtochukwu Edewor

Software Developer and Community Builder

- Abuja, FCT, Nigeria
- iamjohnsomto@gmail.com 
  ↓ +2348184424196

- https://github.com/Boliboe
- IamJSomtochukwu
- in John Somtochukwu
- M John Somtochukwu
- Boliboe

Hello, I am currently a Software Developer and Community Builder based in Abuja, Nigeria. For over four years, I have been actively building some tech and helping non tech communities grow together. I also have delved into a range of positions that I see myself as a generalist. Currently, I am exploring the prospect of segregated Data Security and Bioinformatics to create awareness about data management and biotech in Africa.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **CUEL - Onsite, Nigeria**

(May 2018 - Jan 2020)

Technical Assistant

- As a Technical Assistant, I recommended and sort after devices and technologies, driving high performances between other departments in the organization.
- Supervised the creation of a management system between its distribution and acquisition department.
- Contributed to the development and implementation of communication and quality software tools, increasing the general output of my team.

### **CUEL** - Onsite, Nigeria

(Apr 2020 - Feb 2021)

**Operations Manager** 

- As an Operations manager at CUEL, I had to help set up other outlets and branches within the country.
- Facilitated the creation of a logistics department, increasing the efficiency of the organization during the pandemic.
- Contributed to the redeployment of members across stations and branches, setting up effective communication systems.
- Developed and demonstrated strong problem-solving, critical thinking, communication skills and a passion for learning new tools and methodologies, to contribute to the success of the team and the organization.

## Happy Chicken - Remote, Nigeria

(Mar 2022 - Nov 2022)

Audit Lead

- As the Lead Auditor I collected financial records of the organization ensuring they are up-to-date.
- Implementing best practices and tools for gathering, analyzing and documenting data and records, resulting in a clear and actionable plan that aligned with industry standards.

### SETCO - Onsite, Nigeria

(Nov 2022 - Present)

Technical Assistant

- Established and maintained effective channels between clients and management, providing timely reports about clients complaints and resolving conflicts with an efficiency of over 79%.
- Developed software and communication channels, breaching the divide existing between management and clients.

Plogging Nigeria (Jan 2020 - Present)

Volunteer

• Regularly participated in Plogging Nigeria Club events, contributing to the removal of litter in the community and promoting a cleaner health and environment.

- Distributed informative materials about Plogging Nigeria Club, its mission and goals encouraging family,
   friends and neighbors to participate and promote environmental awareness.
- Sought out educational resources and information related to environmental sustainability to better enhance and contribute to a greener and more sustainable future.

ROTARACT UNN (Jan 2021 - Nov 2022)

Fellow/Volunteer

- Participated in Rotaract UNN events and workshops focused on developing leadership skills amongst young professionals and students.
- As a member of Rotaract UNN, I developed a sense of efficiency and community development through the act
  of service. Participated in many charity outreaches, assisting communities maintaining feedback with other
  communities.

**Students Developers Club** 

(Jan 2018 - Nov 2022)

Team Lead

- Coordinating and executing events and seminars focused on technology for participants to learn new skills, network with professionals, and explore career pathways.
- Engaging local partners and stakeholders, building relationships with other communities and securing resources to support new members in the community.
- Developed and deployed web and mobile applications using different programming tools.

NACOS (Jun 2018 - Dec 2022)

**Executive Member** 

- Acted as Member representing NACOS in the Student Union Government promoting its aspirations and mission to a wider audience through events, conferences and social media.
- Co-facilitated conferences and conventions around the country and hosted webinars with the aim of promoting enthusiasm for science and technology.
- Supported the first ever Digital registration and voting system and facilitated its adoption on campus.

**SKILLS & INTERESTS** 

Data Security Bioinformatics

Web3 Project Planning

Public Speaking Community Management

**EDUCATION** 

University of Nigeria Nsukka (Oct 2017 - Jan 2022)

Bachelor's of Science, Computer Science